Mansfield (Connecticut) League of Women Voters Records 2005.0159
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Mansfield (Connecticut) League of Women Voters Records
undated, 1942-2011
2005.0159
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
5.95 Linear feet
The materials that compose the records of the Mansfield League of Women Voters in this collection begin with minutes documenting a meeting that took place on 5 February, 1942. As the League gained strength in membership and purpose the records of its activities have included: organizational documents such as histories of the League, by-laws, Board policies, Board rosters and membership directories; minutes of Board meetings, annual meetings, and sporadic general membership meetings; financial reports relating to budgetary matters; newsletters; study reports based on intensive study of mostly local issues.
5.45 linear feet.
Mansfield (CT) League of Women Voters.
History
The Mansfield League of Women Voters ( MLWV) was organized in 1941 and is an affiliate of the national League of Women Voters (LWVUS). It is a non-profit political organization dedicated to encouraging informed and active participation in government and politics. The LWVUS and its state affiliates do not support or oppose candidates or political parties. However, they do take positions on issues and work to advance these positions. Support of positions is determined through membership consensus after objective study.
To encourage participation in government the MLWV conducts voter registration drives, sponsors forums at which voters meet the candidates, and compiles and disseminates voter information. Publications on the process of government and various governmental issues are distributed to the public at no cost.
During the years since its founding members of the MLWV have worked on many national, state and local issues with notable success. Among the local achievements in which the informational studies and supportive actions of the MLWV have played a decisive role are:
Town Planning and Zoning
Public Library Services
Organization of Town Ordinances
Full-Day Public Kindergarten
Before- and After-School Programs
Revisions of Town Charter
Public Library Services
Day Care Center
Hazardous Household Waste Collection
Environmental Conservation and Preservation
Foreign Language Beginning in Grade 2
Bicycle and Walking Paths
Assisted-Living Housing for Aging, Moderate-Income Residents (in progress, Sept 2008)
Later High School Start Time (in progress, Sept 2008)
PUBLIC SERVICES:
Know Your Towns Fair
Meet the Candidates Night
Legislative Breakfast
Publication of Voters Guide
Publication and Distribution of Know Your Town Booklet
Hospitality at Town Budget Meetings
Public Issue Forums
Additional information about the Mansfield League of Women Voters is available on its website.
Scope and Contents
The materials that compose the records of the Mansfield League of Women Voters (MLWV) in this collection begin with minutes documenting a meeting that took place on 5 February 1942. As the MLWV gained strength in membership and purpose the records of its activities have included: organizational documents such as histories of the League, by-laws, Board policies, Board rosters and membership directories; minutes of Board meetings, annual meetings, and sporadic general membership meetings; financial reports relating to budgetary matters; newsletters; study reports based on intensive study of mostly local issues.
The relative completeness of these records reflects what has been made available to this collection from many current and past members of the MLWV. Additional materials of both a historic and current nature will be added as they become available.
Arrangement
Series I. Organizational Records ( undated, 1946-2009 ) contains general records of the organization and documentation of several significant committees and activities. Please note that "Know Your Town Fair" changed to "Know Your Towns Fair" in 2006.
Series II. Minutes ( 1942-2008 ) contains minutes and reports of annual, board and general meetings. The dates for this series are inclusive and do not indicate those that are missing.
Series III. Studies and Positions ( undated, 1951-2009 ) contains the research, notes, references and working papers of the League study groups.
Series IV. Programs ( undated, 1975-2009 ) includes documentation of occasional programs organized, presented and/or sponsored by the MLWV.
Series V: Scrapbooks ( 1950-2003 ) documents the activities and interests of the organization organized chronologically.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to Connecticut organizations, history and politics. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Handbook for Mansfield Voters Dodd
Know Your Town Dodd
Newsletter Dodd Periodicals
Community Center Forum 2005-0159.vr1
MLVW Filming 2005-0159.vr2
Did My Vote Really Count on 11/4? 2005-0159.dvd1
Call It Democracy 2005-0159.dvd2
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection with the exception of Membership materials. The Membership lists/directories/rosters for the most recent ten years are available only to members of the MLWV.
Acquisition Information
The Dodd Research Center was selected as the official repository for the Mansfield LWV records in 2005. Materials have been added irregularly since November 2005.
League of Women Voters of Mansfield (Mansfield, Conn.); Administrative Records.; Audio cassettes.; Audio visual materials.; By-Laws.; Correspondence.; Financial Records.; Fliers. [printed matter]; Histories.; Mansfield (Conn.); Minutes.; Newsletters.; Notebooks.; Notes.; Photocopies.; Photographs.; Publications.; Scrapbooks.; Videocassettes.
- Series I: Organizational Records, undated, 1946-2009
  - General, undated, 1946-2010
    - 75th Anniversary: The Yesterday Show (script), 1995 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
    - Annual Reports to League of Women Voters of Connecticut, 2003, 2005 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
    - Board Job Descriptions, State and Local, undated, 1984-2011 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
    - Board Member lists, 1969-2011 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - Board Policies, 1952-2008 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - Brochures, 2009-2010 (Box 3:, Folder 198)
    - Budget/Finance/Accounting, State and Local, 1957-1962 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - Bylaws, 1967-1993 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
    - Bylaws, State and National, 2000-2001 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1955-1984 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
    - Ephemera and clippings, undated (Box 1:, Folder 10)
    - Finance: Annual Fundraising Appeal, 1982-2008 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
    - Finance: Fundraisers, undated, 1983 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
    - Finance: Support to two area high schools to send students to SIR, 2001-2006 (Box 4, Folder 217)
    - Historical materials, 1962-2001 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
    - Interest sheets and Surveys, 1981-2004 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
    - League Basics, 2008 March (Box 1:, Folder 15)
    - League of Women Voters, State and National, undated, 1946-1986 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
    - League of Women Voters, Mansfield, Information Booklets, 1974-1975 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
    - Legislative Action: Legislative Breakfast, 2007-2011 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
    - Nominating Committee, 1970-2007 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
    - Secretary "kits,", undated, 1983-1993 (Box 1:, Folder 20)
    - Telephone "chains,", 1985 (Box 1:, Folder 21)
    - Finance: Donation to UConn's Dodd Research Center, 2006- (Box 4, Folder 218)
  - Membership, 1947-2009
    - 1947-1956 (Box 1:, Folder 22)
    - 1960-1979 (Box 1:, Folder 23)
    - 1980-1989 (Box 1:, Folder 24)
    - 1990-1999 (Box 4, Folder 220)
    - 2000-2009
      Access
      Directories restricted to MLWV members only.
  - Know Your Town Fair, 1987-2009
    - History, 1987-1995 (Box 1:, Folder 25)
    - 1996 (Box 1:, Folder 26)
    - 1997 (Box 1:, Folder 27)
    - 1998 (Box 1:, Folder 28)
    - 1999 (Box 1:, Folder 29)
    - 2000 (Box 1:, Folder 30)
    - 2001 (Box 1:, Folder 31)
    - 2002 (Box 1:, Folder 32)
    - Voters Service, undated, 1955-2009
      - Resource materials, undated, 1982-2008 (Box 1:, Folder 40)
      - Candidate's meeting minutes, 1955-1959 (Box 1:, Folder 41)
      - Candidate's night
        - 1992 (Box 1:, Folder 42)
        - 1993 (Box 1:, Folder 43)
        - 1995 (Box 1:, Folder 44)
        - 1996 (Box 1:, Folder 45)
        - 1997 (Box 1:, Folder 46)
        - 1998 (Box 1:, Folder 47)
        - 1999 (Box 1:, Folder 48)
        - 2000 (Box 1:, Folder 49)
        - 2001 (Box 1:, Folder 50)
        - 2002 (Box 1:, Folder 51)
        - 2003 (Box 1:, Folder 52)
        - 2004 (Box 1:, Folder 53)
        - 2006 (Box 1:, Folder 54)
        - 2007 (Box 1:, Folder 55)
        - 2008 (Box 3:, Folder 200)
        - 2009 (Box 4:, Folder 209)
        - 2009 (Box 4:, Folder 209)
        - 2010 (Box 4:, Folder 214)
        - 2011 (Box 4:, Folder 216)
      - Voters guides for state and federal elections, 1956-1992 (Box 1:, Folder 56)
      - Voters guides for municipal elections, 1969-2007 (Box 1:, Folder 57)
      - Voter, 1990 (Box 1:, Folder 58)
      - Voter Fact sheet on Liquor referendum, undated (Box 1:, Folder 59)
    - 2003 (Box 1:, Folder 33)
    - 2004 (Box 1:, Folder 34)
    - 2005 (Box 1:, Folder 35)
    - 2006 (Box 1:, Folder 36)
    - 2007 (Box 1:, Folder 37)
    - 2008 (Box 1:, Folder 38)
    - 2009 (Box 3:, Folder 197)
- Series II: Minutes, 1942-2008
  - Noon Unit Meetings, 2007 (Box 3:, Folder 201)
  - Annual Meeting minutes and reports, 1943-2009
    - 1943-1949 (Box 1:, Folder 60)
    - 1950-1959 (Box 1:, Folder 61)
    - 1960-1969 (Box 1:, Folder 62)
    - 1970-1979 (Box 1:, Folder 63)
    - 1980-1989 (Box 1:, Folder 64)
    - 1990-1999 (Box 1:, Folder 65)
    - 2000-2008 (Box 1:, Folder 66)
    - 2010-2011 (Box 4, Folder 215)
  - Board meeting minutes, 1942-2008
    - 1942-1945 (Box 1:, Folder 67)
    - 1946 (Box 1:, Folder 68)
    - 1947 (Box 1:, Folder 69)
    - 1947-1948 (Box 1:, Folder 70)
    - 1948-1949 (Box 1:, Folder 71)
    - 1949-1960 (Box 1:, Folder 72)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 2:, Folder 73)
    - 1951-1952 (Box 2:, Folder 74)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 2:, Folder 75)
    - 1953-1954 (Box 2:, Folder 76)
    - 1954-1955 (Box 2:, Folder 77)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 2:, Folder 78)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 2:, Folder 79)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 2:, Folder 80)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 2:, Folder 81)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 2:, Folder 82)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 2:, Folder 83)
    - 1961-1962 (Box 2:, Folder 84)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 2:, Folder 85)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 2:, Folder 86)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 2:, Folder 87)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 2:, Folder 88)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 2:, Folder 89)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 2:, Folder 90)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 2:, Folder 91)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 2:, Folder 92)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 2:, Folder 93)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 2:, Folder 94)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 2:, Folder 95)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 2:, Folder 96)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 2:, Folder 97)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 2:, Folder 98)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 2:, Folder 99)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 2:, Folder 100)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 2:, Folder 101)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 2:, Folder 102)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 2:, Folder 103)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 2:, Folder 104)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 2:, Folder 105)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 2:, Folder 106)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 2:, Folder 107)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 2:, Folder 108)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 2:, Folder 109)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 2:, Folder 110)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 2:, Folder 111)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 2:, Folder 112)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 2:, Folder 113)
    - 1991-1992 (Box 2:, Folder 114)
    - 1992-1993 (Box 2:, Folder 115)
    - 1993-1994 (Box 2:, Folder 116)
    - 1994-1995 (Box 2:, Folder 117)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 2:, Folder 118)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 2:, Folder 119)
    - 1997-1998 (Box 2:, Folder 120)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 2:, Folder 121)
    - 1999-2000 (Box 2:, Folder 122)
    - 2000-2001 (Box 2:, Folder 123)
    - 2001-2002 (Box 2:, Folder 124)
    - 2002-2003 (Box 2:, Folder 125)
    - 2003-2004 (Box 2:, Folder 126)
    - 2004-2005 (Box 2:, Folder 127)
    - 2005-2006 (Box 2:, Folder 128)
    - 2006-2007 (Box 2:, Folder 129)
    - 2007-2008 (Box 2:, Folder 130)
    - 2008-2009 (Box 4, Folder 210)
    - 2009-2010 (Box 4, Folder 211)
    - 2010-2011 (Box 4, Folder 212)
  - General Membership meeting minutes, 1942-1964
    - 1942-1949 (Box 2:, Folder 131)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 2:, Folder 132)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 2:, Folder 133)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 2:, Folder 134)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 2:, Folder 135)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 2:, Folder 136)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 2:, Folder 137)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 2:, Folder 138)
    - 1961-1962 (Box 2:, Folder 139)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 2:, Folder 140)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 2:, Folder 141)
- Series III: Studies and Positions, undated, 1951-2009
  - Alternative Living for Adolescents Study, 1980-1982 (Box 2:, Folder 142)
  - Annual Report Study, undated (Box 2:, Folder 143)
  - Before- and After-School Study, 1999-2000 (Box 2:, Folder 144)
  - Bergin Correctional Institution Pre-release Program, 2010 September (Box 4, Folder 219)
  - Charter Revision Study, 1973-1976 (Box 2:, Folder 145)
  - Child Care Study, 1986-1987 (Box 2:, Folder 146)
  - Community Conversation on Early Care and Education, 2003-2004 (Box 2:, Folder 147)
  - Day Care Mini-Study, 1978-1979 (Box 3:, Folder 148)
  - E.O. Smith High School Reorganization, undated, 1973-1986 (Box 3:, Folder 149)
  - Foreign Languages in the Elementary School Study, 1995-1996 (Box 3:, Folder 150)
  - Guidance Services in the Public Schools Study, 1978-1979 (Box 3:, Folder 151-152)
  - Hazardous Waste, undated (Box 3:, Folder 153)
  - Hazardous Waste, 1981 (Box 3:, Folder 154)
  - Hazardous Waste, 1982-1993 (Box 3:, Folder 155)
  - Hazardous Waste Seminar, 1983 April (Box 3:, Folder 156)
  - Healthcare Study, undated, 1985-1986 (Box 3:, Folder 157)
  - Housing Code Study, undated, 1968-1976 (Box 3:, Folder 158)
  - Housing Master Plan Report Summary, 1983 December (Box 3:, Folder 159)
  - Housing Study, undated, 1968-1972 (Box 3:, Folder 160-161)
  - Housing Study, undated, 1971-1976 (Box 3:, Folder 162)
  - Housing Study, undated, 1974-1976 (Box 3:, Folder 163)
  - Housing Study, 1972-1974 (Box 3:, Folder 164)
  - Housing Study, 1974-1975 (Box 3:, Folder 165)
  - Human Resources Study, undated, 1966-1976 (Box 3:, Folder 166)
  - Land Use Planning in Mansfield, undated, 1972-1974 (Box 3:, Folder 167)
  - Later High School Start Study, 2005 (Box 3:, Folder 168)
  - Leisure Time and Recreation Study, 1973-1974 (Box 3:, Folder 169)
  - Local Studies and Positions, 1970-1977 (Box 3:, Folder 170)
  - LWVCT Ethics in Government Study, 2004-2005 (Box 3:, Folder 202)
  - LWVCT Ethics in Government Study, 2004-2005 (Box 3, Folder 202)
  - LWVUS National Popular Vote (NPV) Compact Study, 2008-2009 (Box 4:, Folder 206-207)
  - Mansfield Training School Property Task Force and Study, undated, 1974-1996 (Box 3:, Folder 171)
  - Mental Health Care in the Public Schools Study, 1975-1977 (Box 3:, Folder 172)
  - Mobile Home Study, undated, 1972-1975 (Box 3:, Folder 173)
  - National Popular Vote (NPV) Compact Study, 2008-2009 (Box 4, Folder 206-207)
  - Open Space in Mansfield, undated, 1971-1980 (Box 3:, Folder 174)
  - Peer Project on Equal Access to Computers Study, 1984-1986 (Box 3:, Folder 175)
  - Plan of Development Study, undated, 1970-1984 (Box 3:, Folder 176)
  - Prison at Mansfield Training School Site, 1987 (Box 3:, Folder 177)
  - Public Education Financing, 1957-1959 (Box 3:, Folder 178)
  - Public Library Services Study, undated, 1973-1977 (Box 3:, Folder 179)
  - Public Safety Services Study Update, 1984 April (Box 3:, Folder 180)
  - Public Transportation in Connecticut, undated, 1973-1978 (Box 3:, Folder 181)
  - Public Transportation in Mansfield, undated, 1971-1979 (Box 3:, Folder 182)
  - School Libraries Study, 1951-1952 (Box 3:, Folder 183)
  - School Services Study: Kindergarten and Art Supervision, undated, 1963-1964 (Box 3:, Folder 184)
  - Solid Waste and Recycling, undated, 1971-1978 (Box 3:, Folder 185)
  - State of Connecticut Spending Cap Study, 2001-2007 (Box 3, Box 203)
    - 2001-2002 (Box 203)
    - 2002-2007 (Box 3, Folder 204)
    - 2001-2005 (Box 3, Folder 205)
  - State of Connecticut Tax Study, 1997-1998 (Box 3:, Folder 186)
  - Structure of Town Government Study, undated, 1965-1967 (Box 3:, Folder 187)
  - Town Charter, 1967-1970 (Box 3:, Folder 188)
  - Uniform Fiscal Year, 1972 (Box 3:, Folder 189)
  - U.S. Immigration Study and Consensus, 2007 November 29 (Box 3:, Folder 190)
- Series IV: Programs, 1975-2009
  - Affordable Housing, 2007 April 25 (Box 3:, Folder 191)
  - Local Affairs Forums, 1975-1976 (Box 3:, Folder 192)
  - Water and Sewer for Mansfield Retirement Community and Informational meeting, 1979 (Box 3:, Folder 193)
  - Solar Home Tour, undated, 1980-1981 (Box 3:, Folder 194)
  - Electoral College Program, 2002 November 19 (Box 4:, Folder 208)
  - Town Budget Meetings: Eat Dessert First, 2008 May 13, 2010 May 11 (Box 3:, Folder 195)
  - Water Wise? Panel, 2008 March 5 (Box 3:, Folder 196)
  - Storrs Center Forum, 2009 April 29 (Box 3:, Folder 199)
  - Storrs Center Public Forum, 2009 April 29 (Box 3, Folder 199)
  - What's Best for Mansfield? School Building Forum, 2010 April 13 (Box 4, Folder 213)
- Series V: Scrapbooks, 1950-2003
  - 1950-1970 (Other 2005-0159_, Volume 1)
  - 1970-1990 (Other 2005-0159_, Volume 2)
  - 1991 May - 1997 May (Other 2005-0159_, Volume 3)
  - 1997-2003 (Other 2005-0159_, Volume 4)